appointy.com 2018-10-13

# Appointy :: Privacy Policy

Appointy Software Inc. and its affiliates (“Appointy,” “we,” “us,” “our,” or the “Company”) are committed to protecting the privacy of individuals who visit the Company’s Web sites (“Visitors”), individuals who register to use the Services as defined below (“Customers”, “Client”.). This Privacy Statement describes Appointy’s privacy practices in relation to the use of the Company’s Web sites and the related applications, services, and programs offered by Appointy (collectively, the “Services”), as well as individuals’ choices regarding use, access and correction of personal information. 

If you have questions or complaints regarding Appointy’s Privacy Statement or associated practices, please contact us by emailing us at [contact@appointy.com](mailto:contact@appointy.com). 

  1. ### Web sites covered

This Privacy Statement covers the information practices, including how the Company collects, uses, shares and secures the personal information you provide, of Web sites that link to this Privacy Statement (collectively referred to as “Appointy’s Web sites” or “the Company’s Web sites”). 

Appointy, is an online scheduling software that run on the Company’s [https://appointy.com](https://www.appointy.com/) platform. 

Appointy.com Sites enable Appointy and Appointy’s customers to create Web sites and applications that run natively on the Appointy platform. When Appointy.com Web sites are posted by Appointy, the site will link to this Privacy Statement, and this Privacy Statement applies. 

Appointy’s Web sites may contain links to other Web sites. The information practices or the content of such other Web sites is governed by the privacy statements of such other Web sites. The Company encourages you to review the privacy statements of other Web sites to understand their information practices. 

  2. ### Information collected

    * When expressing an interest in obtaining additional information about the Services, or registering to use the Web sites or other Services, Appointy requires you to provide the Company with personal contact information, such as name, company name, address, phone number, and email address (“Required Contact Information”). 
    * When purchasing the Services, Appointy may also require you to provide billing information, such as billing name and address, credit card number, and the number of employees within the organization that will be using the Services (“Billing Information”). 
    * "Publishing Information": We also collect information you submit through our Site or to us for publication on the Site using the publishing tools there. By submitting Publishing Information, you consent to its publication to the extent such information is not Personal Data. 
    * Required Contact Information, Billing Information, Publishing Information and any other information you submit to Appointy to or through the Services are referred to collectively as "Data." 
    * As you navigate the Company’s Web sites, Appointy may also collect information through the use of commonly-used information-gathering tools, such as cookies and Web beacons (“Web Site Navigational Information”). Web Site Navigational Information includes standard information from your Web browser (such as browser type and browser language), your Internet Protocol (“IP”) address, and the actions you take on the Company’s Web sites (such as the Web pages viewed and the links clicked). For additional information about the collection of Web Site Navigational Information by Appointy and others, please read the “Web Site Navigational Information” section further below in this policy. 
    * Through our “import contacts” feature option, we may also collect information such as the name, company name, address, phone number or email address of contacts that you choose to share with us. When you provide us with personal information about your contacts, we will only use this information for the specific reason for which it is provided, such as to add new records to your Appointy account. 
    * Information Collected by Clients - A User (“User” means a person or entity that uses the Service) may store or upload data into the Service. Appointy has no direct relationship with the non Client Users whose Personal Data it may host as part of Client Data. Each Client is responsible for providing notice to Users who are its customers and third persons concerning the purpose for which the Client collects their Personal Data and how this Personal Data is processed in or through the Service as part of Client Data. 

  3. ### Use of information collected

The Company uses Data about Appointy Customers to perform the services requested. For example, if you fill out a “Request a callback” Web form, the Company will use the information provided to contact you about your interest in the Services. 

The Company may also use Data about Appointy Customers for marketing purposes. For example, the Company may use information you provide to contact you to further discuss your interest in the Services and to send you information regarding the Company, its affiliates, and its partners, such as information about promotions or events. 

Appointy uses Web Site Navigational Information to operate and improve the Company’s Web sites. The Company may also use Web Site Navigational Information alone or in combination with Data about Appointy Customers to provide personalized information about the Company. For additional information about the use of Web Site Navigational Information, please read the "Web Site Navigational Information" section further below in this policy. 

Appointy may partner with third parties to display advertising on our Web sites and Services or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our third-party partners may use cookies or similar technologies provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests. If you wish to opt out of interest-based advertising, please notify us via email, or if located in the European Union click [here](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/). Please note you will continue to receive generic ads. 

  4. ### Web Site Navigational Information

#### Cookies, Web Beacons and IP Addresses

Appointy uses commonly-used information-gathering tools, such as cookies and Web beacons, to collect information as you navigate the Company’s Web sites (“Web Site Navigational Information”). As described more fully below, we and our partners use these cookies or similar technologies to analyze trends, administer Web sites and Services, track users’ movements around our Web sites and Services, serve targeted advertisements and gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. This section describes the types of Web Site Navigational Information used on the Company’s Web sites and Services, and how this information may be used. 

#### Cookies

Appointy uses cookies to make interactions with the Company’s Web sites easy and meaningful. When you visit one of the Company’s Web sites, Appointy’s servers send a cookie to your computer or device. Standing alone, cookies do not personally identify you; they merely recognize your Web browser. Unless you choose to identify yourself to Appointy, either by responding to a promotional offer, opening an account, or filling out a Web form (such as a “Request a call-back” or a “14 Day Free Trial” Web form) or have previously identified yourself to Appointy, you remain anonymous to the Company.   
Appointy uses cookies that are session-based and persistent-based. Session cookies exist only during one session. They disappear from your computer or device when you close your browser software or turn off your computer. Persistent cookies remain on your computer or device after you close your browser or turn off your computer. You can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level, but if you choose to disable cookies, it may limit your use of certain features or functions on our Web sites or Services.   
The following sets out how appointy.com uses different categories of cookies and your options for managing cookies’ settings: 

Type of Cookies | Description | Managing Settings  
---|---|---  
Required cookies |  Required cookies enable you to navigate the Company’s Web sites and use its features, such as accessing secure areas of the Web sites and using Appointy Services.   
If you have chosen to identify yourself to Appointy, the Company may place on your browser cookies containing an encrypted, unique identifier. These cookies allow the Company to uniquely identify you when you are logged into the Web sites and Services and to process your online transactions and requests.  | Because required cookies are essential to operate the Company’s Web sites and the Services, there is no option to opt out of these cookies.  
Functionality cookies |  Functionality cookies allow the Company’s Web sites and Services to remember information you have entered or choices you make (such as your username, language, or your region) and provide enhanced, more personal features. These cookies also enable you to optimize your use of Appointy’s Web sites and Services after logging in. These cookies can also be used to remember changes you have made to text size, fonts and other parts of web pages that you can customize. 

Functional cookies may also be used to improve how the Company's Web sites and Services function and perform, to enhance and customize your interactions with the Company, and to help us provide you with more relevant messages, including marketing communications. These cookies collect information about how Visitors use our Web sites and Services, including which pages visitors go to most often and if they receive error messages from certain pages. 

Appointy may use its own technology (under the Appointy brand name or an affiliated brand name) or third parties to track and analyze usage and volume statistical information from Visitors, Attendees, and Customers, to provide enhanced interactions and more relevant communications, and to track the performance of the Company's advertisements. 

Appointy and it's third-party partners may also utilize HTML5 local storage or Flash cookies for these purposes. Flash cookies and HTML local storage are different from browser cookies because of the amount of, type of, and how data is stored. Appointy also uses Flash cookies, to store your preferences or display content based upon what you view on our Web sites and Services to personalize your visit. 

|  To learn more about how to control cookies using your browser settings [click here](http://www.aboutcookies.org/).   
To learn how to manage privacy and storage settings for Flash cookies [click here](https://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager.html#117118).   
Targeting or Advertising cookies |  Appointy may sometimes use cookies delivered by third parties to show you ads for Appointy products and services that we think may interest you on any devices you may use and to track the performance of Company advertisements. For example, in these cases, cookies remember information such as which browsers have visited the Company’s Web sites. The information provided to third parties does not include personal information, but this information may be re-associated with personal information after the Company receives it. If Appointy is using one of its own cookie-related products on our own Website, then a cookie related to ads may appear on our Web site under the Appointy or one of our affiliated company's name. 

Appointy may also contract with third-party advertising networks that collect IP addresses and other information from Web beacons (see below) on the Company’s Web sites and Services, from emails, and on third-party Web sites. Ad networks follow your online activities over time and across different sites or other online services by collecting Web Site Navigational Information through automated means, including through the use of cookies. These technologies may recognize you across the different devices you use, such as a desktop or laptop computer, smartphone or tablet. Third parties use this information to provide advertisements about products and services tailored to your interests. You may see these advertisements on other Web sites or mobile applications on any of your devices. This process also helps us manage and track the effectiveness of our marketing efforts. Third parties, with whom the Company partners to provide certain features on our Web sites or to display advertising based upon your Web browsing activity, use Flash cookies to collect and store information. Flash cookies are different from browser cookies because of the amount of, type of, and how data is stored. 

|  To learn more about these and other advertising networks and your ability to opt out of collection by certain third party, please visit their respective websites. 

To learn how to manage privacy and storage settings for Flash cookies [click here](https://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager.html#117118). Various browsers may offer their own management tools for removing HTML5 local storage.   
  
#### Web Beacons

Appointy may use Web beacons alone or in conjunction with cookies to compile information about Customers and Visitors’ usage of the Company’s Web sites and interaction with emails from the Company. Web beacons are clear electronic images that can recognize certain types of information on your computer, such as cookies, when you viewed a particular Web site or Service tied to the Web beacon, and a description of a Web site or Service tied to the Web beacon. For example, Appointy may place Web beacons in marketing emails that notify the Company when you click on a link in the email that directs you to one of the Company’s Web sites. Appointy uses Web beacons to operate and improve the Company’s Web sites, Services and email communications. 

#### Log Files, IP Addresses, URLs and Other Data

As is true of most Web sites, we gather certain information automatically to analyze trends in the aggregate and administer our Web sites and Services. This information may include your Internet Protocol (IP) address (or the proxy server you use to access the World Wide Web), device and application identification numbers, your location, your browser type, your Internet service provider and/or mobile carrier, the pages and files you viewed, your searches, your operating system and system configuration information, and date/time stamps associated with your usage. Due to Internet communications standards, when you visit or use the Company’s Websites and Services, we automatically receive the URL of the website from which you came and the website to which you go when you leave our Website. This information is used to analyze overall trends, to help us improve our Websites and Services, to track and aggregate non-personal information, and to provide the Websites and Services. For example, Appointy uses IP addresses to monitor the regions from which Customers and Visitors navigate the Company’s Web sites. Appointy also collects IP addresses from Customers when they log into the Services as part of the Company’s “Identity Confirmation” and “IP Range Restrictions” security features. 

#### Social Media Features and Single Sign-on

The Company’s Web sites may use social media features, such as the Facebook “like” button (“Social Media Features”). These features may collect your IP address and which page you are visiting on the Company’s Web site, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. You may be given the option by such Social Media Features to post information about your activities on the Company’s Web site to a profile page of yours that is provided by a third party social media network in order to share with others within your network. Social Media Features are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on the Company’s Web site. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing the relevant Social Media Features. Appointy also allows you to log in to certain of our Web sites and Services using sign-in services such as Facebook Connect. These services will authenticate your identity and provide you the option to share certain personal information with us such as your name and email address to pre-populate our sign-up form. 

#### Do Not Track

Currently, various browsers — including Internet Explorer, Firefox, and Safari — offer a “do not track” or “DNT” option that relies on a technology known as a DNT header, which sends a signal to Web sites’ visited by the user about the user's browser DNT preference setting. Appointy does not currently commit to responding to browsers' DNT signals with respect to the Company's Web sites, in part, because no common industry standard for DNT has been adopted by industry groups, technology companies or regulators, including no consistent standard of interpreting user intent. Appointy takes privacy and meaningful choice seriously and will make efforts to continue to monitor developments around DNT browser technology and the implementation of a standard. 

  5. ### Public forums, and customer testimonials

Appointy may provide bulletin boards, blogs, or chat rooms on the Company’s Web sites. Any personal information you choose to submit in such a forum may be read, collected, or used by others who visit these forums, and may be used to send you unsolicited messages. Appointy is not responsible for the personal information you choose to submit in these forums.   
Appointy posts a list of Customers and testimonials on the Company’s Web sites that contain information such as Customer names and titles. Appointy obtains the consent of each Customer prior to posting any information on such a list or posting testimonials. 

  6. ### Sharing of information collected

#### Service Providers

Appointy may share Data about Appointy Visitors, and Customers with the Company’s contracted service providers so that these service providers can provide services on our behalf. These service providers are authorized to use your personal information only as necessary to provide the requested services to us. Without limiting the foregoing, Appointy may also share Data about Appointy Visitors, and Customers with the Company’s service providers to ensure the quality of information provided, and with third–party social networking and media Web sites, such as Facebook, for marketing and advertising on those Web sites. Unless described in this Privacy Statement, Appointy does not share, sell, rent, or trade any information with third parties for their promotional purposes. 

#### Appointy Affiliates

The Company may share Data about Appointy Customers with other companies in order to work with them, including affiliates of Appointy. For example, the Company may need to share Data about Appointy Customers with other companies within the Appointy group for customer support, marketing, technical operations and account management purposes. 

#### Business Partners

From time to time, Appointy may partner with other companies to jointly offer products, services, or programs (such as webinars or downloadable content) such as our Reserve with Google partnership. If you purchase, specifically express interest in, or register for a jointly–offered product, service, or program from or through Appointy, the Company may share Data about Appointy Customers collected in connection with your purchase or expression of interest with our partner(s). Appointy does not control our business partners’ use of the Data about Appointy Customers that we collect, and their use of the information will be in accordance with their own privacy policies. If you do not wish for your information to be shared in this manner, you may opt not to purchase or specifically express interest in a jointly offered product or service. 

#### Third Parties

Section 4 of this Privacy Statement, Web Site Navigational Information, specifically addresses the information we or third parties collect through cookies and web beacons, and how you can control cookies through your Web browsers. We may also disclose your personal information to any third party with your prior consent. 

#### Billing

Appointy uses a third-party service provider to manage credit card processing. This service provider is not permitted to store, retain, or use Billing Information except for the sole purpose of credit card processing on the Company’s behalf. 

#### Publishing Information

All of your Publishing Information will be publicly available on the Site and therefore accessible by any internet user. Any Publishing Information that you disclose to Apoointy becomes public information and you relinquish any proprietary rights (including but not limited to the rights of confidentiality and copyrights) in such information. You should exercise caution when deciding to include personal or proprietary information in the Publishing Information that you submit to us. 

#### Compelled Disclosure

Appointy reserves the right to use or disclose information provided if required by law or if the Company reasonably believes that use or disclosure is necessary to protect the Company’s rights and/or to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process. 

  7. ### International transfer of information collected

The Company primarily stores Data about Appointy Customers and Data about Appointy in the European Economic Region. To facilitate Appointy’s global operations, the Company may transfer and access such information from around the world, including from other countries in which the Company has operations. A list of the Company’s global offices is available [here](https://www.appointy.com/contactUs/). This Privacy Statement shall apply even if Appointy transfers Data about Appointy Customers to other countries. 

  8. ### Communications preferences

Appointy offers Visitors, Customers, and Attendees who provide contact information a means to choose how the Company uses the information provided. You may manage your receipt of marketing and non-transactional communications by clicking on the “unsubscribe” link located on the bottom of the Company’s marketing emails. Additionally, you may unsubscribe by contacting us using the information in the “Contacting Us" section below. 

  9. ### Correcting and updating your information

Appointy may retain your information for a period of time consistent with the original purpose of collection. For instance, we may retain your information during the time in which you have an account to use our Web sites or Services and for a reasonable period of time afterward. We also may retain your information during the period of time needed for Appointy to pursue our legitimate business interests, conduct audits, comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes and enforce our agreements.   
You may request to review, correct, delete or otherwise modify any of the personal information that you have previously provided to us through the Company’s Web sites and Services. If you have registered for an account with Appointy, you may generally update your user settings, profile, organization’s settings or event registration by logging into the applicable Website or Service with your username and password and editing your settings or profile. To update your billing information, discontinue your account, and/or request return or deletion of Your Data associated with your account, please contact your account representative or the customer service team for the applicable Service. For other requests to access, correct, modify or delete Your Data, please review the “Contacting Us” section below. Requests to access, change, or delete your information will be addressed within a reasonable timeframe. If you are an employee of an Appointy customer, you may also wish to contact your company’s system administrator for assistance in correcting or updating your information. 

  10. ### Customer Data

Appointy’s Customers may electronically submit data or information to the Services for hosting and processing purposes ("Customer Data"). Appointy will not review, share, distribute, or reference any such Customer Data except as provided in Appointy’s [Terms of use](https://www.appointy.com/termsofuse/), or as may be required by law. In accordance with Appointy’s Terms of Use, Appointy may access Customer Data only for the purpose of providing the Services or preventing or addressing service or technical problems or as may be required by law.   
Appointy acknowledges that you have the right to access your personal information. If personal information pertaining to you as an individual has been submitted to us by an Appointy customer and you wish to exercise any rights you may have to access, correct, amend, or delete such data, please inquire with our customer directly. Because Appointy personnel have limited ability to access data our customers submit to our Services, if you wish to make your request directly to Appointy, please provide the name of the Appointy customer who submitted your data to our Services. We will refer your request to that customer, and will support them as needed in responding to your request within a reasonable timeframe.

  11. ### Security

Appointy uses robust security measures to protect Data about Appointy Customers. Because the Company uses the Services to maintain Data about Appointy Customers, this information, which is stored in the Services, is secured in the same manner as described [here](https://www.appointy.com/gdpr)

  12. ### Mobile applications

Without limiting the generality of this Privacy Statement, in addition to information gathered through its Web sites or submitted to its Services, Appointy may obtain information through applications (“Mobile Applications”) that Customers or their authorized individuals (“Staff”) download to, and run on, their mobile devices (“Devices”). Mobile Applications provided by Appointy may obtain information from, or access data stored on, Users’ Devices to provide services related to the relevant Mobile Application. For example, a Mobile Application may: access a camera on a User’s Device to enable the User to upload photographs to the Services. Information obtained to provide Mobile Application services may include information obtained in preparation for anticipated updates to those services. Mobile Applications may transmit information to and from Devices to provide the Mobile Application services.   
Mobile Applications may provide Appointy with information related to Users’ use of the Mobile Application services, information regarding Users’ computer systems, and information regarding Users’ interaction with Mobile Applications, which Appointy may use to provide and improve the Mobile Application services. For example, all actions taken in a Mobile Application may be logged, along with associated information (such as the time of day when each action was taken). Appointy may also share anonymous data about these actions with third party providers of analytics services. In addition, if a User downloads an Appointy Mobile Application after clicking on a third-party mobile advertisement for the Mobile Application or for Appointy, the third-party advertiser may provide Appointy with certain information, such as the User’s Device identification information, which Appointy may use to track the performance of its advertising campaigns.   
Customers may configure Appointy Mobile Application services, and the information accessed or obtained by the Mobile Application on a User’s Device may be affected by the Customer’s configuration. Information accessed or obtained by the Mobile Application on a User’s Device may be accessible to the Customer and its organization, depending on the intended functionality of the Mobile Application. Appointy may provide updated versions of its Mobile Applications. If your mobile device’s settings permit, those updates will be downloaded and installed automatically on your mobile device. By installing an Appointy Mobile Application on your mobile device, you consent to the downloading and updating of that Mobile Application.   
Notices and contractual terms related to a particular Mobile Application may be found in the End User License Agreement or relevant terms of service for that application. The Company encourages you to review the End User License Agreement or relevant terms of service related to any Mobile Applications you download, install, use, or otherwise interact with to understand that Mobile Application’s information practices. The Mobile Application’s access to information through a User’s Device does not cause that information to be "Customer Data" under Appointy’s Terms Of Use with the Customer or under this Privacy Statement, except as follows: To the extent that a User uses a Mobile Application to submit electronic data and information to a Customer account on our Services pursuant to the Customer's Service Agreement with Appointy (or a similar agreement that governs the Customer’s subscription(s) to Appointy’s Services), that information constitutes “Customer Data” as defined in such agreement, and the provisions of that agreement with respect to privacy and security of such data will apply. 

  13. ### Children's Privacy

Our Service does not address and is not directed towards anyone under the age of 16 ("Children"). We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from anyone under the age of 16. If you are a parent or guardian and you are aware that your Child has provided us with Personal Data, please contact us. If we become aware that we have collected Personal Data from children without verification of parental consent, we take steps to remove that information from our servers. 

  14. ### Changes to this Privacy Statement

We may update our Privacy Policy from time to time. We will notify you of any changes by posting the new Privacy Policy on this page. You are advised to review this Privacy Policy periodically for any changes. Changes to this Privacy Policy are effective when they are posted on this page. 

  15. ### Contacting us

Questions regarding this Privacy Statement or the information practices of the Company’s Web sites and Services should be directed to Us by emailing us at: [contact@appointy.com](mailto:contact@appointy.com)

Appointy Software Inc.,  
16 Corning Ave, Suite 136,  
Milpitas, CA, USA 95035
